<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Studentpad</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>One stop Destination for perfect preparation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 11:18:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/cropped-Studentpad-tbg-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Studentpad</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Everything You Need to Know About Applying for NEET Exams</title>
		<link>/applying-for-neet-exams/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kpranjal]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 10:44:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh no! You clicked on a wrong category]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=442</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Indian Medical Council Act of 1956 established the National Eligibility cum Entrance Test (NEET) to test and evaluate the aptitude of candidates applying to be doctors in India. It was first implemented in 2013 and has been held every year since. Over 1,100 medical colleges accept applicants based on their NEET score, so it’s&#8230;&#160;<a href="/applying-for-neet-exams/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Everything You Need to Know About Applying for NEET Exams</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/applying-for-neet-exams/">Everything You Need to Know About Applying for NEET Exams</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Studentpad</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<script async src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     data-ad-slot="1507983555"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<p>The Indian Medical Council Act of 1956 established the National Eligibility cum Entrance Test (NEET) to test and evaluate the aptitude of candidates applying to be doctors in India. It was first implemented in 2013 and has been held every year since. Over 1,100 medical colleges accept applicants based on their NEET score, so it’s essential that you know how to apply for NEET exams if you want to be a doctor in India or abroad.</p>



<h3>Understanding the NEET Eligibility Criteria</h3>



<p>Before you can apply, you&#8217;ll need to understand your eligibility. The first step in doing so is understanding what NEET stands for and what exactly it&#8217;s trying to test. The National Eligibility cum Entrance Test or NEET is an examination held every year in India by Central Board of Secondary Education (CBSE) on behalf of Medical Council of India (MCI). It is conducted as per schedule released by CBSE twice a year, once in May and once in November. This exam is intended to test students who wish to pursue a career in medicine after completion of their Class 12 board exams from all over India under one single exam.</p>



<h3>Filling in the Application Form</h3>



<p>When you’re applying for a National Eligibility cum Entrance Test (NEET), your eligibility needs to be validated by filling in an application form. The application form consists of personal information and academic details such as marks in previous years and expected marks. For every question on academic details, you need to keep copies of your mark sheets and certificates ready. If you are applying from a school, mark sheets of secondary as well as higher secondary classes have to be submitted; if you are applying from a college or university, mark sheets of all courses must be submitted. After submitting your application form, there will be further validation steps that might include proof of identity, a medical examination, proof of age and many more depending on which exam you are writing.</p>



<h3>Submitting the Application</h3>



<p>After you’ve registered, you’ll need to submit your application online. There are no hard copies or PDFs of your application; it has to be submitted online. For Indian applicants, there are two deadlines: one from May 15-31, and another from July 1-21. If you’re applying for foreign candidates, check out your country-specific dates here . If you miss a deadline (and many do), you can still apply outside of these dates but at an additional cost of Rs 500 (approximately $8 USD). Note that if your exam is in January, February or March and you apply after June 21, 2022, then your application will not be accepted.</p>



<h2>Uploading Documents</h2>



<p>It’s important that you have all your documents ready before you start your application. See below a list of what documents are required: (1) 10th Mark sheet or equivalent certificate; (2) 12th Mark sheet or equivalent certificate; (3) Degree Certificate issued by the University/Institution where study was completed and wherever applicable, Graduation Degree obtained in foreign countries; (4) Caste/Tribe/Disability Certificate issued by Mandal Revenue Officer on a plain paper with photographs affixed on it. Any other additional certificates should be sent as additional copies to above specified points.</p>



<h3>Paying Fees</h3>



<p>Unlike in some countries, you’ll need to pay all fees up front. The two most common fees are application and examination fees. Application fees are anywhere from 600 – 2,000 INR ($9–$30) and exam fees run anywhere from 3,000 – 4,500 INR ($50–$75). Once you’ve paid your fees, you should receive an acceptance letter within 10-15 days with further instructions on how to register for a test date. If that seems like a lot of money, it is: applying for NEET exams can get expensive quickly if you&#8217;re not careful about planning ahead. However, it&#8217;s possible—and often necessary—to find ways of paying for NEET exams other than cash out of pocket.</p>



<h3>Receiving Admit Cards &amp; Mark Sheets</h3>



<p>Once you receive an admit card for NEET exams, you should write down your roll number on it and keep it safe. Although NEET is held twice a year, your exam date might change from what was mentioned in your admit card. So, be sure to double-check for any amendments once you&#8217;ve received your confirmatory email about your NEET exam schedule. Mark sheets for exams are posted online one month after NEET has been conducted—so make sure that you regularly check for results and match them with documents like your admission letter or mark sheet if need be.</p>



<script async src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     data-ad-slot="1507983555"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/applying-for-neet-exams/">Everything You Need to Know About Applying for NEET Exams</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Studentpad</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are you planning to take the JEE exams? Here&#8217;s how to apply!</title>
		<link>/are-you-planning-to-take-the-jee-exams-heres-how-to-apply/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kpranjal]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 04:18:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh no! You clicked on a wrong category]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=438</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you’re interested in studying engineering in India, then the JEE (Joint Entrance Examination) is one of the first steps you’ll need to take on your way to college. The JEE has two sections: JEE Main and JEE Advanced, both of which test your knowledge of physics, chemistry, and mathematics. Before you can apply to&#8230;&#160;<a href="/are-you-planning-to-take-the-jee-exams-heres-how-to-apply/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Are you planning to take the JEE exams? Here&#8217;s how to apply!</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/are-you-planning-to-take-the-jee-exams-heres-how-to-apply/">Are you planning to take the JEE exams? Here&#8217;s how to apply!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Studentpad</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<script async src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     data-ad-slot="1507983555"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<p>If you’re interested in studying engineering in India, then the JEE (Joint Entrance Examination) is one of the first steps you’ll need to take on your way to college. The JEE has two sections: JEE Main and JEE Advanced, both of which test your knowledge of physics, chemistry, and mathematics. Before you can apply to take either exam, though, you’ll need to familiarize yourself with how the process works and start preparing early so that you can get through the application process as smoothly as possible. Here’s how to apply for JEE exams!</p>



<h3>What is the JEE (Main)?</h3>



<p>The Joint Entrance Examination Main, popularly known as JEE (Main), is a national level competitive examination conducted for admission to undergraduate engineering programmes in institutes that are governed by AICTE. The exam is conducted at two levels- JEE (Main) and JEE (Advanced). One can opt for both or only one of these levels of exams. Those who do not qualify in either/both of these levels can also appear for other state level engineering entrance examinations like BITSAT, WBJEEM, among others.</p>



<h3>When Do I Need To Apply For The JEE (Main)?</h3>



<p>While many students are aware of when and where they need to take the exam, some aren’t sure about when they need to fill out their application. You’ll want to submit your application as soon as possible—around February or March. It’s best if you can also submit your documents early too—before August is ideal. Depending on what kind of candidate you are, you may have more time or less time in which to apply. If that all sounds a little confusing, don’t worry—we have all of your answers right here.</p>



<h3>Document Requirements</h3>



<p>An applicant must submit either of two sets of documents, depending on their qualifications. To qualify under Local Candidates category: 1) SSLC (or Equivalent) and 2) Plus two certificate that is qualifying for admission in engineering/ technology courses run by any recognized Board in India or a Certificate / Diploma in Engineering/ Technology as defined by AIE/ AICTE, New Delhi. An applicant must submit either of two sets of documents, depending on their qualifications.</p>



<h3>Eligibility Criteria For Applying To The JEE Main Exam</h3>



<p>To be eligible for applying to JEE Main, one must have completed Class 12 from a recognized board in India. For students who wish to appear for JEE Main 2022, but are studying under boards which do not conduct their examinations in May 2022 (such as CBSE or ISC), should appear for a board exam in 2021. Further, one must fulfill the eligibility criteria as specified by their state government and school authority. For detailed information on eligibility criteria, check out jee.nic.in</p>



<h3>Fees and Payment Mode</h3>



<p>Candidates may pay a non-refundable application fee of Rs. 1000/- (Rupees One Thousand only) in form of Demand Draft drawn in favour of Board of Studies, IIT Bombay payable at Mumbai by registered/speed post or through Net Banking/Credit Card or by using Credit Cards provided by State Bank of India(SBI). The payment should be made from any SBI Branch located at Mumbai through credit card/debit card issued by SBI. Fee for SC, ST candidates and Female candidates is Rs. 800/- only.</p>



<h3>Dates And Important Details</h3>



<p>The Joint Entrance Examination (JEE) is a common engineering entrance test conducted by an independent examination board named Central Board of Secondary Education (CBSE). The exam is held twice a year; one in April and another in January. In order to sit for these tests, students must register beforehand and pay fees. Applicants must be 17 or 18 years old on or before December 31st of their final year, must have completed 10+2 level education (science stream), as well as qualify through minimum class/percentage requirements. The specific details will vary depending on where you live within India. For example, if you’re applying from within Delhi, certain cutoffs may differ from those if you’re living in Mumbai or elsewhere.</p>



<h3>Previous Year Question Papers</h3>



<p>It’s important that you familiarize yourself with previous year papers before taking a test like JEE. It’s also crucial that you spend a few weeks practicing for these exams. One of your goals during practice should be to answer as many questions correctly as possible. In fact, each question has a valuable piece of information that can help guide your future preparation; don’t forget to write down what that insight is! Familiarizing yourself with past exam questions will also allow you to notice patterns in question topics, which will come in handy when it comes time for exam day preparation and answering.</p>



<p>If you are looking for free JEE previous year papers, download them from here &#8211; https://www.studentpad.live/jee-main-free-previous-year-question . You can also check out some of our other posts related to JEE Main Preparation Tips and Tricks:)</p>



<script async src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     data-ad-slot="1507983555"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/are-you-planning-to-take-the-jee-exams-heres-how-to-apply/">Are you planning to take the JEE exams? Here&#8217;s how to apply!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Studentpad</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 10 Best Institutes for NEET in India</title>
		<link>/top-10-best-institutes-for-neet-in-india/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kpranjal]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 14:02:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh no! You clicked on a wrong category]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=428</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The National Eligibility-cum-Entrance Test (NEET) is an all-India common medical entrance exam conducted by the Central Board of Secondary Education (CBSE). It serves as the sole criterion to take admission into various MBBS and BDS courses in India’s government and private medical colleges. The NEET exam replaced the All India Pre Medical Test (AIPMT) and&#8230;&#160;<a href="/top-10-best-institutes-for-neet-in-india/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Top 10 Best Institutes for NEET in India</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/top-10-best-institutes-for-neet-in-india/">Top 10 Best Institutes for NEET in India</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Studentpad</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<script async src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     data-ad-slot="1507983555"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<p>The National Eligibility-cum-Entrance Test (NEET) is an all-India common medical entrance exam conducted by the Central Board of Secondary Education (CBSE). It serves as the sole criterion to take admission into various MBBS and BDS courses in India’s government and private medical colleges. The NEET exam replaced the All India Pre Medical Test (AIPMT) and other state-level entrance exams to make the admission process more fair and transparent, with the goal of eventually eliminating confusion around multiple entrance exams.</p>



<h3>1) Motilal Nehru National Institute of Technology Allahabad</h3>



<p>The Motilal Nehru National Institute of Technology is a public, national engineering institute located at Allahabad in Uttar Pradesh. The Motilal Nehru National Institute of Technology was established on June 14, 1958 and it was named after Pandit Motilal Nehru, an eminent Indian nationalist leader who founded Jamia Millia Islamia. The institute is affiliated to Uttar Pradesh Technical University (UPTU) and approved by AICTE and NITA. Apart from its undergraduate programs, MNIT has postgraduate programs like M.Tech., MBA, MCA and PhD. It offers regular courses under semester system as well as distance learning courses (online). Recently a new Department of Biosciences &amp; Bioengineering has been introduced in MNIT.</p>



<h3>2) Sant Gadge Baba Amravati University</h3>



<p>Sant Gadge Baba Amravati University is located in Maharashtra. It is an autonomous public university established by Government of Maharashtra. The institute was founded on 16th May-1973. Sant Gadge Baba Amravati University was formerly known as Central Agricultural University (CAU). This institute is one of a pioneer institution that offers under graduate programs to Bachelors’ and Post Graduate Programs to Masters’ and doctorate level courses. This institution also organizes various undergraduate and postgraduate courses like BA, BSc, BEd, MA, MEd, MBA and Ph.D degree programs.</p>



<h3>3) Sri Venkateswara University</h3>



<p>Established way back in 1954, SVU is one of India’s leading centers of higher education. It has seven campuses located across Andhra Pradesh, Telangana and Tamil Nadu, with a staff strength of more than 3,000. In fact, it offers courses in around 25 disciplines including engineering and technology; law; arts; and medicine and health sciences among others. The university has a rich history behind it: For example, its campus at Tirupati was designed by internationally renowned architect Le Corbusier.</p>



<h3>4) Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University Anantapur</h3>



<p>This university has done exceptionally well when it comes to producing successful candidates who are appearing for various entrance exams. According to a report by TOI, more than 70% of its students have successfully made it to medical colleges in Karnataka, Andhra Pradesh and Kerala. The infrastructure of JNTU Anantapur is quite good with huge spaces that are meant for outdoor sports. It was ranked as one of India’s best colleges by Business Today and had featured on QS Top Universities list from 2016-2018. It also featured among India’s top 20 research institutions back in 2013 and is currently working on an iGEM project under an agreement with Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT).</p>



<h3>5) Anna University Chennai</h3>



<p>Anna University of Technology, formerly known as Anna University is a public state university. It is located at Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India. It was formed by merging four older universities, namely Bharathidasan University, Theagaraya College of Engineering, Madras Institute of Technology and College of Engineering Guindy. The university was formed on 4 September 2007 and started functioning from 3 October 2007 with 36 colleges (22 under Anna University and 14 under its autonomous colleges) from around Chennai city and nearby districts. When it started functioning there were 22 schools which offered undergraduate courses while 13 provided postgraduate courses in various streams under five faculties: engineering &amp; technology; sciences; architecture &amp; planning; humanities &amp; social sciences; business administration.</p>



<h3>6) Dr. B.R. Ambedkar National Institute of Technology Jalandhar</h3>



<p>The Dr. B.R. Ambedkar National Institute of Technology is one of India’s leading engineering colleges, with its Jalandhar campus located near Kapurthala. Established by an act of Parliament, it caters to students from all over India, including international students from neighbouring countries such as Nepal and Bangladesh. The institute was established in 1960 by then-Prime Minister Jawaharlal Nehru and has played a key role in training India’s most brilliant engineers ever since its founding. It offers courses across seven undergraduate streams.</p>



<h3>7) JNTU Hyderabad</h3>



<p>Andhra Pradesh’s capital city, Visakhapatnam, is home to one of best medical schools in India. The Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University (JNTU) was established by an act of parliament on December 23, 1989 and has become a key institution for producing medical professionals in South India. JNTU offers both graduate and postgraduate programs through seven colleges, two autonomous institutes and an active research arm. JNTU-Hyderabad’s College of Medical Sciences graduates over 900 students annually from its highly ranked undergraduate program – ranked among top ten public universities in Andhra Pradesh.</p>



<h3>8) Jodhpur National University, Jodhpur</h3>



<p>Founded in 1966, Jodhpur National University has gained a reputation as one of top universities that offers NEET preparatory courses. The university provides high-quality instruction and is accredited by NABL. Admissions are through entrance exams. In addition to providing NEET tutoring, Jodhpur National University also offers a three-year undergraduate program and a two-year graduate program. Facilities include Wi-Fi access on campus, computers with internet access, digital libraries containing textbooks and ebooks, online virtual classrooms and more. There are state-of-the art labs where students can work on group projects related to their field of study.</p>



<h3>9) Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal</h3>



<p>Manipal Academy of Higher Education (MAHE) has emerged as one of India’s premier institutes for higher education. Located near Udupi, a small coastal town in Karnataka, MAHE is known to provide excellent healthcare facilities and educational infrastructure. The campus boasts of a sophisticated library system with over 120,000 books and a computer lab that supports over 2000 online users. It also has guest houses, hostels and shopping complexes to support students. MAHE offers NEET Exam coaching across all major cities like Bangalore, Chennai, Mumbai, Hyderabad and Kolkata etc., so that students can choose a study center convenient to them. Faculty members are drawn from renowned institutions like Harvard University and IIT Delhi among others.</p>



<h3>10) Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University Delhi (GGSIPU Delhi)</h3>



<p>A full-fledged residential university with hostels, three middles schools, primary schools and pre-primary schools. The university has library, sports complex and indoor stadiums. It holds educational programmes such as workshops, seminars and symposiums. It imparts training to different hospitals affiliated to it regarding its medical courses. Some of its popular courses are BHMS (Bachelor of Homeopathic Medicine &amp; Surgery), BAMS (Bachelor of Ayurvedic Medicine &amp; Surgery), BCA (Bachelor of Computer Application) and BA (Hons.) Economics to name a few.</p>



<script async src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     data-ad-slot="1507983555"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/top-10-best-institutes-for-neet-in-india/">Top 10 Best Institutes for NEET in India</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Studentpad</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Top 10 Institutes for JEE-Main in India</title>
		<link>/the-top-10-institutes-for-jee-main-in-india/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kpranjal]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 13:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh no! You clicked on a wrong category]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=421</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Tracking down the best institutes in India for the JEE-Main entrance exam can be time-consuming and frustrating, but we’ve done the hard work of narrowing it down to 10 of the best institutes in India. Whether you’re looking for one of the top government schools in India or some of the leading private schools and&#8230;&#160;<a href="/the-top-10-institutes-for-jee-main-in-india/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">The Top 10 Institutes for JEE-Main in India</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-top-10-institutes-for-jee-main-in-india/">The Top 10 Institutes for JEE-Main in India</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Studentpad</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<script async src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     data-ad-slot="1507983555"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<p>Tracking down the best institutes in India for the JEE-Main entrance exam can be time-consuming and frustrating, but we’ve done the hard work of narrowing it down to 10 of the best institutes in India. Whether you’re looking for one of the top government schools in India or some of the leading private schools and coaching centers, these are some of the best institutes to help you prepare for your JEE-Main entrance exam.</p>



<h3>1) IIT Bombay</h3>



<p>IIT Bombay is one of India’s premiere institutes, offering a high-quality education to students who are interested in engineering, technology and science. According to Forbes, IIT Bombay is ranked sixth among universities worldwide; it also was awarded a gold rating by QS World University Rankings. IIT Bombay offers many excellent opportunities to students and faculty alike. In addition to its small size – there are just over 3,000 undergraduate students and 400 graduate students at IIT Bombay – it has a strong culture of student research that puts undergraduates right alongside graduate students and professors on research projects.</p>



<h3>2) IIT Delhi</h3>



<p>The Institute of Technology at Delhi, colloquially known as IIT Delhi, is one of the best institutes of technology offering undergraduate and postgraduate courses in engineering and science. The institute is headquartered at Hauz Khas Campus and covers an area of over 545 acres with a 120 acre biological park. The campus was ranked 28th among engineering colleges by Outlook India magazine. It offers various courses in eight main departments, namely civil engineering, computer science and engineering, electrical engineering, electronic and communication engineering, materials science and metallurgical engineering, mechanical engineering, chemical engineering and bioengineering.</p>



<h3>3) IIT Kanpur</h3>



<p>The Indian Institute of Technology Kanpur (IITK) is one of the eight new IITs, which were established after a proposal from former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh to then HRD Minister Kapil Sibal. The institution is currently affiliated with UPTU (University of Petroleum and Technology, UP) until it becomes independent. In its initial years, IITK planned to focus on interdisciplinary research and was set up with department wise specializations instead of research labs. It has 26 undergraduate courses leading to BTech degrees along with six MTech programmes. Facilities include state-of-the-art lecture theatres, academic and guest houses, hostels and student canteens among others.</p>



<h3>4) IIT Kharagpur</h3>



<p>IIT Kharagpur is one of many engineering colleges that are administered by an IIT. Its campus is spread across 2,000 acres and it&#8217;s currently ranked among some of India&#8217;s best universities. It offers Bachelors, Masters and Doctoral degrees in various fields and it has been consistently ranked as one of India&#8217;s top institutions for research, education and employment. There are nearly 3,000 faculty members teaching over 12,000 students at any given time. As far as facilities go, IIT Kharagpur boasts a library containing more than 1 million books – making it one of Asia’s biggest collections – along with computer labs with internet access.</p>



<h3>5) BITS Pilani – Goa Campus</h3>



<p>BITS Pilani – Goa Campus is one of India’s oldest and most respected educational institutions. In recent years, it has also become popular among foreign students looking to pursue education abroad. The campus has a rich heritage, with many notable figures associated with it including freedom fighter Gopal Krishna Gokhale, who advocated British education for Indians; industrialist Dhirubhai Ambani, who made it possible for local students to attend BITS with financial aid; and Mani Bhavanrao Pant Pratinidhi, a member of Maharaja Sayajirao Gaekwad III’s governing council.</p>



<h3>6) Vellore Institute of Technology</h3>



<p>Vellore Institute of Technology (VIT) is a private deemed university located in Vellore, Tamil Nadu, India. Established in 1984 as Vellore Engineering College by V. Srinivasan, chairman of The Lakshmi Chandrashekharan Group (Lakshmi Entities), which owns and operates educational institutions across several states. It was renamed as VIT University in 2001. In 2010, VIT was granted deemed university status by the University Grants Commission (UGC). Over 6500 students are enrolled at present. The student community includes undergraduates and postgraduates from across 92 districts of Tamil Nadu and other parts of India who live on campus or off campus local area hostels.</p>



<h3>7) Indian Institute of Science (IISc), Bangalore</h3>



<p>IISc is a premiere engineering institute located in Bangalore. It is often regarded as one of India’s best institutes. For engineering, it’s been ranked among Asia’s top three best universities. In fact, according to QS World University Rankings 2014/15, IISc ranks second only to Nanyang Technological University (NTU) Singapore among Asian universities that focus on engineering and technology. The research conducted at IISc has been continuously rated among Asia’s top five over several years by Shanghai Ranking&#8217;s Global Ranking of Academic Subjects by subject specialists and scholars. The colleges curriculum includes topics such as experimental laboratories and high quality academic programs.</p>



<h3>8) Madras Institute of Technology, Chennai</h3>



<p>The Madras Institute of Technology is one of India’s most prestigious institutes. It was founded in 1873 by American missionaries and at first only accepted high school graduates as students, but later changed its admission policy to require that all students have a degree before they can attend. This means that you will graduate with a bachelor’s degree, which is excellent preparation for applying to a master’s program after college if you want to continue your education without having to retake any courses. The institution offers about 40 programs in engineering, technology, architecture and management fields and over 6,000 students attend classes each year. Most of Mtech&#8217;s enrollment comes from Tamil Nadu state, but some international students also attend from countries such as Sri Lanka and Nepal.</p>



<h3>9) National Institute of Technology, Calicut (NITC)</h3>



<p>Located at Malappuram district of Kerala, NITC was established in 1960 and is recognized as an Institute of National Importance by AICTE. The institute admits undergraduates through JEE Advanced while MTech admissions are done through GATE. Over 80% of its 16,000 alumni have made a mark as successful entrepreneurs and research professionals. NITC is a premier institute that has contributed towards development in various fields like IT, Electronics and Communication etc.</p>



<h3>10) College of Engineering, Pune (COEP), Pune</h3>



<p>COEP is a government college and one of the best institutes for engineering in Pune. It provides a high quality education and has been listed among some of country’s best institutes. In 2014, it was ranked 17th among technical institutions by Outlook Magazine. Admission to COEP is through an engineering entrance exam known as JEE MAIN which is conducted by CBSE . COEP attracts most of its students from western Maharashtra and other parts of India.</p>



<script async src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     data-ad-slot="1507983555"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-top-10-institutes-for-jee-main-in-india/">The Top 10 Institutes for JEE-Main in India</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Studentpad</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Prepare for MHT-CET-XII – Tips and Tricks for Free Study Material</title>
		<link>/how-to-prepare-for-mht-cet-xii-tips-and-tricks-for-free-study-material/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kpranjal]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 04:36:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh no! You clicked on a wrong category]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=410</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Top 5 Preparation Tips for MHT-CET-XII Here are some tips that will help you prepare yourself for MHT-CET-XII. I have listed these tips in a way that they can easily be remembered with abbreviation. Make sure that you follow these tips while preparing to crack MHT-CET-XII. 1.Always keep a separate notebook for notes Notes are&#8230;&#160;<a href="/how-to-prepare-for-mht-cet-xii-tips-and-tricks-for-free-study-material/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">How to Prepare for MHT-CET-XII – Tips and Tricks for Free Study Material</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-prepare-for-mht-cet-xii-tips-and-tricks-for-free-study-material/">How to Prepare for MHT-CET-XII – Tips and Tricks for Free Study Material</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Studentpad</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<script async src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     data-ad-slot="1507983555"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<h2>Top 5 Preparation Tips for MHT-CET-XII</h2>



<p>Here are some tips that will help you prepare yourself for MHT-CET-XII. I have listed these tips in a way that they can easily be remembered with abbreviation. Make sure that you follow these tips while preparing to crack MHT-CET-XII.</p>



<p><strong>1.Always keep a separate notebook for notes</strong></p>



<p>Notes are your best friend during exams, so make sure that you make them in a way that is easy to understand. Focus on creating concepts rather than just copying text from books or notes. These notes should be short but meaningful, as you’ll be writing down anything that could help you in future; something which may prove useful at some point of time.</p>



<p><strong>2.Practice Sample Papers and Previous Year Papers</strong></p>



<p>Practice sample papers are very important when it comes to getting a good rank in your MHT-CET-XII exams. A lot of students think that they can study just by reading their books, but that is not true at all! You need practice as well, which you can get only through sample papers and previous year question papers. These papers will help you understand how examiners think, so make sure that you solve each paper carefully and then compare your answers with those given in solutions.</p>



<p><strong>3.Try studying from videos</strong></p>



<p>If you are someone who is not fond of reading or if you want a shorter way to study, then watching videos will be perfect for you. I am sure that everyone of us has watched some educational videos before, so we all know how informative they can be. If you do not have time to read a book on a topic, then make sure that you watch at least one video on it. It would really help in better understanding concepts which might prove difficult otherwise.</p>



<p><strong>4.Don’t waste your time in finding free study material</strong></p>



<p>If you are looking for some free study material, it is your last attempt. There are some websites which will give you what you want, but most of them are fake ones. They just need your email id in return of their service. Don’t fall prey to them. You can find what you want only through Google or any search engine because everything is free online now a days. But be careful while downloading anything because everything is not genuine on internet these days! You can simply download your free study material for free from our website. All the resources are attached below.</p>



<p><strong>5.Always try to choose a right institute</strong></p>



<p>Choosing a right institute is very important as you will be going there every day. It is not just about getting a rank in your exam but also having a good time with your friends. You can interact with smart people there and they will help you understand concepts better. Secondly, you also need to experience the environment before taking admission. I recommend taking a demo class before admission. It’s important that are you comfortable with the teaching technique of the teachers.</p>



<h2>Best ways to study without wasting time</h2>



<p>Time is perhaps one of your biggest constraints in your quest to get ahead of others and secure a seat in a reputed college. Learning from sample papers are an excellent way to save time, especially when it comes to writing. Students often complain that there’s no time for revision. Revision is an integral part of learning, if you don’t revise what you have learnt, chances are you will forget some or all of it by exam day. You should ideally spend at least 15 minutes every day revising what you have studied so far. Revising even five minutes a day can help you retain information better, thus saving precious time on exam day. If you want to study more efficiently, try making flashcards out of important formulas and concepts. Flashcards are an excellent tool for self-testing yourself while studying. It also helps strengthen your memory because it forces you to recall information instead of just reading it over again. If you make use of these tips along with regular practice tests and mock exams, then I am sure you will be able to ace your exams!</p>



<h2>Getting the Most out of Coaching Classes</h2>



<p>The best way to prepare for a competitive exam like MHT-CET-XII is by taking coaching classes. Make sure you take coaching classes that have teachers who are certified in their subject, as they’ll be able to answer all your doubts and help you with important tips on how to approach each question. Always attend classes with an open mind; even if you find it boring or unnecessary, listen attentively until your teacher has finished talking so that you can take away whatever knowledge he/she imparts. And most importantly, don’t forget to practice! There’s no substitute for practice. You should always try to solve past papers of previous years when studying for an exam like MHT-CET-XII. This will give you an idea of what kind of questions are asked in these exams and will also allow you to get familiarized with them. Practice makes perfect!</p>



<h2>Free Online Resources For Aspirants</h2>



<p>MHT-CET-XII free sample papers with answer and solution – https://www.studentpad.live/mht-cet-xii-free-sample-papers/</p>



<script async src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     data-ad-slot="1507983555"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-prepare-for-mht-cet-xii-tips-and-tricks-for-free-study-material/">How to Prepare for MHT-CET-XII – Tips and Tricks for Free Study Material</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Studentpad</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Prepare for MHT-CET-XI – Tips and Tricks for Free Study Material</title>
		<link>/how-to-prepare-for-neet-tips-and-tricks-for-free-study-material-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kpranjal]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 04:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh no! You clicked on a wrong category]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=403</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Top 5 Preparation Tips for MHT-CET-XI Here are some tips that will help you prepare yourself for MHT-CET-XI. I have listed these tips in a way that they can easily be remembered with abbreviation. Make sure that you follow these tips while preparing to crack MHT-CET-XI. 1.Always keep a separate notebook for notes Notes are&#8230;&#160;<a href="/how-to-prepare-for-neet-tips-and-tricks-for-free-study-material-2/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">How to Prepare for MHT-CET-XI – Tips and Tricks for Free Study Material</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-prepare-for-neet-tips-and-tricks-for-free-study-material-2/">How to Prepare for MHT-CET-XI – Tips and Tricks for Free Study Material</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Studentpad</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<script async src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     data-ad-slot="1507983555"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<h2>Top 5 Preparation Tips for MHT-CET-XI</h2>



<p><br>Here are some tips that will help you prepare yourself for MHT-CET-XI. I have listed these tips in a way that they can easily be remembered with abbreviation. Make sure that you follow these tips while preparing to crack MHT-CET-XI.</p>



<p><strong>1.Always keep a separate notebook for notes</strong></p>



<p>Notes are your best friend during exams, so make sure that you make them in a way that is easy to understand. Focus on creating concepts rather than just copying text from books or notes. These notes should be short but meaningful, as you’ll be writing down anything that could help you in future; something which may prove useful at some point of time.</p>



<p><strong>2.Practice Sample Papers and Previous Year Papers</strong></p>



<p>Practice sample papers are very important when it comes to getting a good rank in your MHT-CET-XI exams. A lot of students think that they can study just by reading their books, but that is not true at all! You need practice as well, which you can get only through sample papers and previous year question papers. These papers will help you understand how examiners think, so make sure that you solve each paper carefully and then compare your answers with those given in solutions.</p>



<p><strong>3.Try studying from videos</strong></p>



<p>If you are someone who is not fond of reading or if you want a shorter way to study, then watching videos will be perfect for you. I am sure that everyone of us has watched some educational videos before, so we all know how informative they can be. If you do not have time to read a book on a topic, then make sure that you watch at least one video on it. It would really help in better understanding concepts which might prove difficult otherwise.</p>



<p><strong>4.Don’t waste your time in finding free study material</strong></p>



<p>If you are looking for some free study material, it is your last attempt. There are some websites which will give you what you want, but most of them are fake ones. They just need your email id in return of their service. Don’t fall prey to them. You can find what you want only through Google or any search engine because everything is free online now a days. But be careful while downloading anything because everything is not genuine on internet these days! You can simply download your free study material for free from our website. All the resources are attached below.</p>



<p><strong>5.Always try to choose a right institute</strong></p>



<p>Choosing a right institute is very important as you will be going there every day. It is not just about getting a rank in your exam but also having a good time with your friends. You can interact with smart people there and they will help you understand concepts better. Secondly, you also need to experience the environment before taking admission. I recommend taking a demo class before admission. It’s important that are you comfortable with the teaching technique of the teachers.</p>



<h2><strong>Best ways to study without wasting time</strong><br></h2>



<p>Time is perhaps one of your biggest constraints in your quest to get ahead of others and secure a seat in a reputed college. Learning from sample papers are an excellent way to save time, especially when it comes to writing. Students often complain that there’s no time for revision. Revision is an integral part of learning, if you don’t revise what you have learnt, chances are you will forget some or all of it by exam day. You should ideally spend at least 15 minutes every day revising what you have studied so far. Revising even five minutes a day can help you retain information better, thus saving precious time on exam day. If you want to study more efficiently, try making flashcards out of important formulas and concepts. Flashcards are an excellent tool for self-testing yourself while studying. It also helps strengthen your memory because it forces you to recall information instead of just reading it over again. If you make use of these tips along with regular practice tests and mock exams, then I am sure you will be able to ace your exams!</p>



<h2>Getting the Most out of Coaching Classes<br></h2>



<p>The best way to prepare for a competitive exam like MHT-CET-XI is by taking coaching classes. Make sure you take coaching classes that have teachers who are certified in their subject, as they’ll be able to answer all your doubts and help you with important tips on how to approach each question. Always attend classes with an open mind; even if you find it boring or unnecessary, listen attentively until your teacher has finished talking so that you can take away whatever knowledge he/she imparts. And most importantly, don’t forget to practice! There’s no substitute for practice. You should always try to solve past papers of previous years when studying for an exam like MHT-CET-XI. This will give you an idea of what kind of questions are asked in these exams and will also allow you to get familiarized with them. Practice makes perfect!</p>



<h2>Free Online Resources For Aspirants</h2>



<p><br>MHT-CET-XI free sample papers with answer and solution – <a href="https://www.studentpad.live/mht-cet-xi-free-sample-papers/">https://www.studentpad.live/mht-cet-xi-free-sample-papers/</a></p>



<script async src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     data-ad-slot="1507983555"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-prepare-for-neet-tips-and-tricks-for-free-study-material-2/">How to Prepare for MHT-CET-XI – Tips and Tricks for Free Study Material</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Studentpad</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Prepare for NEET – Tips and Tricks for Free Study Material</title>
		<link>/how-to-prepare-for-neet-tips-and-tricks-for-free-study-material/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kpranjal]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 05:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh no! You clicked on a wrong category]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=384</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A comprehensive step-by-step guide on how to prepare for the NEET examinations, an examination conducted by the National Testing Agency that serves as the gateway to admission in Bachelors and Masters programs at IITs and NITs in India. This article covers important topics like preparation tips, relevant study material, exam pattern, selection process and so&#8230;&#160;<a href="/how-to-prepare-for-neet-tips-and-tricks-for-free-study-material/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">How to Prepare for NEET – Tips and Tricks for Free Study Material</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-prepare-for-neet-tips-and-tricks-for-free-study-material/">How to Prepare for NEET – Tips and Tricks for Free Study Material</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Studentpad</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<script async src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     data-ad-slot="1507983555"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<p>A comprehensive step-by-step guide on how to prepare for the NEET examinations, an examination conducted by the National Testing Agency that serves as the gateway to admission in Bachelors and Masters programs at IITs and NITs in India. This article covers important topics like preparation tips, relevant study material, exam pattern, selection process and so much more. If you’re looking to get into one of the top engineering schools in India through the NEET exams, then this is definitely something you should read!</p>



<h2>Top 5 Preparation Tips for NEET</h2>



<p>Here are some tips that will help you prepare yourself for NEET. I have listed these tips in a way that they can easily be remembered with abbreviation. Make sure that you follow these tips while preparing to crack NEET.</p>



<p><strong>1.Always keep a separate notebook for notes</strong></p>



<p>Notes are your best friend during exams, so make sure that you make them in a way that is easy to understand. Focus on creating concepts rather than just copying text from books or notes. These notes should be short but meaningful, as you’ll be writing down anything that could help you in future; something which may prove useful at some point of time.</p>



<p><strong>2.Practice Sample Papers and Previous Year Papers</strong></p>



<p>Practice sample papers are very important when it comes to getting a good rank in your NEET exams. A lot of students think that they can study just by reading their books, but that is not true at all! You need practice as well, which you can get only through sample papers and previous year question papers. These papers will help you understand how examiners think, so make sure that you solve each paper carefully and then compare your answers with those given in solutions.</p>



<p><strong>3.Try studying from videos</strong></p>



<p>If you are someone who is not fond of reading or if you want a shorter way to study, then watching videos will be perfect for you. I am sure that everyone of us has watched some educational videos before, so we all know how informative they can be. If you do not have time to read a book on a topic, then make sure that you watch at least one video on it. It would really help in better understanding concepts which might prove difficult otherwise.</p>



<p><strong>4.Don’t waste your time in finding free study material</strong></p>



<p>If you are looking for some free study material, it is your last attempt. There are some websites which will give you what you want, but most of them are fake ones. They just need your email id in return of their service. Don’t fall prey to them. You can find what you want only through Google or any search engine because everything is free online now a days. But be careful while downloading anything because everything is not genuine on internet these days! You can simply download your free study material for free from our website. All the resources are attached below.</p>



<p><strong>5. Always try to choose a right institute</strong></p>



<p>Choosing a right institute is very important as you will be going there every day. It is not just about getting a rank in your exam but also having a good time with your friends. You can interact with smart people there and they will help you understand concepts better. Secondly, you also need to experience the environment before taking admission. I recommend taking a demo class before admission. It’s important that are you comfortable with the teaching technique of the teachers.</p>



<h2><strong>Best ways to study without wasting time</strong></h2>



<p>Time is perhaps one of your biggest constraints in your quest to get ahead of others and secure a seat in a reputed college. Learning from sample papers are an excellent way to save time, especially when it comes to writing. Students often complain that there’s no time for revision. Revision is an integral part of learning, if you don’t revise what you have learnt, chances are you will forget some or all of it by exam day. You should ideally spend at least 15 minutes every day revising what you have studied so far. Revising even five minutes a day can help you retain information better, thus saving precious time on exam day. If you want to study more efficiently, try making flashcards out of important formulas and concepts. Flashcards are an excellent tool for self-testing yourself while studying. It also helps strengthen your memory because it forces you to recall information instead of just reading it over again. If you make use of these tips along with regular practice tests and mock exams, then I am sure you will be able to ace your exams!</p>



<h2>Getting the Most out of Coaching Classes</h2>



<p>The best way to prepare for a competitive exam like NEET is by taking coaching classes. Make sure you take coaching classes that have teachers who are certified in their subject, as they’ll be able to answer all your doubts and help you with important tips on how to approach each question. Always attend classes with an open mind; even if you find it boring or unnecessary, listen attentively until your teacher has finished talking so that you can take away whatever knowledge he/she imparts. And most importantly, don’t forget to practice! There’s no substitute for practice. You should always try to solve past papers of previous years when studying for an exam like NEET. This will give you an idea of what kind of questions are asked in these exams and will also allow you to get familiarized with them. Practice makes perfect!</p>



<h2>Free Online Resources For Aspirants</h2>



<p>NEET free sample papers with answer and solution &#8211; https://www.studentpad.live/neet-free-sample-papers/</p>



<p>NEET free Previous year papers with answer and solution &#8211; https://www.studentpad.live/neet-previous-year-question/</p>



<script async src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     data-ad-slot="1507983555"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-prepare-for-neet-tips-and-tricks-for-free-study-material/">How to Prepare for NEET – Tips and Tricks for Free Study Material</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Studentpad</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Prepare for JEE-Main – Tips and Tricks for Free Study Material</title>
		<link>/how-to-prepare-for-jee-main-tips-and-tricks-for-free-study-material/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kpranjal]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 05:57:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh no! You clicked on a wrong category]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=381</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A comprehensive step-by-step guide on how to prepare for the JEE-Main examinations, an examination conducted by the National Testing Agency that serves as the gateway to admission in Bachelors and Masters programs at IITs and NITs in India. This article covers important topics like preparation tips, relevant study material, exam pattern, selection process and so&#8230;&#160;<a href="/how-to-prepare-for-jee-main-tips-and-tricks-for-free-study-material/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">How to Prepare for JEE-Main – Tips and Tricks for Free Study Material</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-prepare-for-jee-main-tips-and-tricks-for-free-study-material/">How to Prepare for JEE-Main – Tips and Tricks for Free Study Material</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Studentpad</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<script async src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     data-ad-slot="1507983555"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<p>A comprehensive step-by-step guide on how to prepare for the JEE-Main examinations, an examination conducted by the National Testing Agency that serves as the gateway to admission in Bachelors and Masters programs at IITs and NITs in India. This article covers important topics like preparation tips, relevant study material, exam pattern, selection process and so much more. If you’re looking to get into one of the top engineering schools in India through the JEE-Main exams, then this is definitely something you should read!</p>



<h2>Top 5 Preparation Tips for JEE</h2>



<p>Here are some tips that will help you prepare yourself for JEE-MAIN. I have listed these tips in a way that they can easily be remembered with abbreviation. Make sure that you follow these tips while preparing to crack JEE.</p>



<p><strong>1.Always keep a separate notebook for notes</strong></p>



<p>Notes are your best friend during exams, so make sure that you make them in a way that is easy to understand. Focus on creating concepts rather than just copying text from books or notes. These notes should be short but meaningful, as you’ll be writing down anything that could help you in future; something which may prove useful at some point of time.</p>



<p><strong>2.Practice Sample Papers and Previous Year Papers</strong></p>



<p>Practice sample papers are very important when it comes to getting a good rank in your JEE exams. A lot of students think that they can study just by reading their books, but that is not true at all! You need practice as well, which you can get only through sample papers and previous year question papers. These papers will help you understand how examiners think, so make sure that you solve each paper carefully and then compare your answers with those given in solutions.</p>



<p><strong>3.Try studying from videos</strong></p>



<p>If you are someone who is not fond of reading or if you want a shorter way to study, then watching videos will be perfect for you. I am sure that everyone of us has watched some educational videos before, so we all know how informative they can be. If you do not have time to read a book on a topic, then make sure that you watch at least one video on it. It would really help in better understanding concepts which might prove difficult otherwise.</p>



<p><strong>4.Don&#8217;t waste your time in finding free study material</strong></p>



<p>If you are looking for some free study material, it is your last attempt. There are some websites which will give you what you want, but most of them are fake ones. They just need your email id in return of their service. Don&#8217;t fall prey to them. You can find what you want only through Google or any search engine because everything is free online now a days. But be careful while downloading anything because everything is not genuine on internet these days! You can simply download your free study material for free from our website. All the resources are attached below.</p>



<p><strong>5. Always try to choose a right institute</strong></p>



<p>Choosing a right institute is very important as you will be going there every day. It is not just about getting a rank in your exam but also having a good time with your friends. You can interact with smart people there and they will help you understand concepts better. Secondly, you also need to experience the environment before taking admission. I recommend taking a demo class before admission. It&#8217;s important that are you comfortable with the teaching technique of the teachers.</p>



<h2>Best ways to study without wasting time</h2>



<p>Time is perhaps one of your biggest constraints in your quest to get ahead of others and secure a seat in a reputed college. Learning from sample papers are an excellent way to save time, especially when it comes to writing. Students often complain that there’s no time for revision. Revision is an integral part of learning, if you don’t revise what you have learnt, chances are you will forget some or all of it by exam day. You should ideally spend at least 15 minutes every day revising what you have studied so far. Revising even five minutes a day can help you retain information better, thus saving precious time on exam day. If you want to study more efficiently, try making flashcards out of important formulas and concepts. Flashcards are an excellent tool for self-testing yourself while studying. It also helps strengthen your memory because it forces you to recall information instead of just reading it over again. If you make use of these tips along with regular practice tests and mock exams, then I am sure you will be able to ace your exams!</p>



<h2>Getting the Most out of Coaching Classes</h2>



<p>The best way to prepare for a competitive exam like JEE is by taking coaching classes. Make sure you take coaching classes that have teachers who are certified in their subject, as they’ll be able to answer all your doubts and help you with important tips on how to approach each question. Always attend classes with an open mind; even if you find it boring or unnecessary, listen attentively until your teacher has finished talking so that you can take away whatever knowledge he/she imparts. And most importantly, don’t forget to practice! There’s no substitute for practice. You should always try to solve past papers of previous years when studying for an exam like JEE. This will give you an idea of what kind of questions are asked in these exams and will also allow you to get familiarized with them. Practice makes perfect!</p>



<h2>Free Online Resources For Aspirants</h2>



<p>JEE-MAIN free sample papers with answer and solution &#8211; https://www.studentpad.live/jee-main-free-sample-papers/</p>



<p>JEE-MAIN free previous year papers with answer and solution &#8211; https://www.studentpad.live/jee-main-free-previous-year-question/</p>



<script async src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-5560563504434511"
     data-ad-slot="1507983555"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-prepare-for-jee-main-tips-and-tricks-for-free-study-material/">How to Prepare for JEE-Main – Tips and Tricks for Free Study Material</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Studentpad</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
